There are many monsters threatening humans.
有許多怪物 威脅著人類
Many brave adventurers stepped forward bravely.
挺身而出的是 眾多勇敢的冒險家
And I,
而我
Alvin, is one of them.
埃爾文就是其中一位
Forming a party with the healer Carla,
與僧侶卡菈組隊
let's continue the adventure today.
今天也持續冒險旅程
DON'T HURT ME, MY HEALER
(這個僧侶有夠煩)
THE TITLE PIG GIRL'S PLACE
(此次的標題) (住宿少女豬)
WHEN ALVIN AND CARLA PLANNED TO STAY IN THE HOTEL, THE OWNER WHO SEEMED NICE
(埃爾文和卡菈打算在旅館住宿時) (看起來人很好的老闆)
REVEALED HER TRUE COLORS BECAUSE OF CARLA. THEN THE NATURE OF AN OLD WOMAN
(因卡菈的緣故露出了真面目) (接著在路上遇到的老婆婆)
"MET ON THE WAY WAS VERY UNEXPECTED." Excuse me.
(其本性令人十分意外) 不好意思
"THIS WORLD IS FULL OF DEMONS AND MONSTERS" We want to stay for one night.
(再次認知這個世界到處都是) 我們想住一晚
"COVERED IN HUMAN SKIN." Puff, welcome to Pig Girl's Place.
(披著人類外皮的魔物和怪物) 噗 歡迎來到住宿少女豬
"AND THE NAME OF THE HOTEL IS PIG GIRL'S PLACE. SOME PEOPLE MAY NOT KNOW WHERE IT COMES FROM." What a great hotel name.
(而旅館的名字是"住宿少女豬" 或許有人不知哏從哪來) 好棒的旅館名字
"IT'S A FAMOUS WORK ANYWAY. THOSE WHO KNOW WILL FEEL SO NOSTALGIC." Puff, thank you very much.
(總之就是部有名的作品 知道的人就會覺得好懷念) 噗 謝謝誇獎
"I HAVEN'T SEEN IT FOR A LONG TIME. I WANT TO SEE IT." How many guests?
(好久沒看了好想看喔) 請問幾位客人呢
"AND I'M IMMERSED IN THESE FEELINGS. THAT'S EPISODE FIVE." Me and someone like a goblin. Two people.
(並沉浸在這些感慨中的第5話) 我和類似哥布林的人 共兩位
-I don't want to stay in a pigsty... -It's a hotel.
-我不想住豬圈… -是旅館
But anyway...
但不管怎麼看…
It's totally a human.
全身上下都是人
But he keeps puffing.
可是他一直噗噗叫
Stop it.
別說了
What are you talking about?
你們在說什麼
Nothing. Please don't mind.
沒什麼 請別在意
It's just goblin's nonsense.
只是哥布林的胡言亂語
If you don't mind, I'll prepare dinner for you two.
不介意的話 我為兩位準備晚餐吧
My interest is cooking.
我的興趣是做料理
-Is this a butcher shop? -It's a hotel.
-這裡是肉舖嗎 -是旅館
What's the menu for dinner?
請問今晚的餐點是什麼
Deep-fried pork cutlet.
炸豬排
-Is it... pork cutlet? -Puff.
-豬排…是嗎 -噗
Deep-fried pork cutlet by killing the same kind. It must be delicious.
同類殺死同類的炸豬排 一定很好吃吧
What an incredible guy.
真是難以置信的傢伙
Hey, you.
你這傢伙
Say it to the person concerned.
要說就對著當事人說
It's so rude.
很沒禮貌耶
What? You also think so, don't you?
什麼 你自己也這麼覺得吧
You're a pathetic creature covered in the skin of a kind human.
你是披著善良人皮的可悲物種
And I'm just an honest person who speaks your mind.
而我只是說出你內心話的誠實人
This is called hypocrisy.
這就是所謂的偽善
And why are you shaking?
然後 妳在晃什麼
It's getting dizzy...
暈了…
Just spit out your evil heart.
乾脆吐出妳的邪惡之心吧
You really didn't find out.
你真的沒發現
That ugly... Personalized protective layer. Was your observation cursed?
那醜陋的…富有個性的防護層 你的觀察力是被人詛咒了嗎
What do you mean?
什麼意思
I mean, that pig isn't a human.
我是說那隻豬不是人類
Pigs aren't humans.
豬本來就不是人類
I mean...
我的意思是…
I'm trapped in the darkness of the eternal land.
我陷入常世國之黑暗
How dare you say I'm a pig...
竟然說我是豬…
Look, it's getting angry. The manager is very angry.
妳看人家怒了 店長超怒的
Is the manager an Iberian pig?
店長是伊比利亞豬嗎
Are you too hungry?
妳是餓昏頭了嗎
How dare you look down on me.
竟敢瞧不起我
The manager's look...
店長的樣子…
Is he going to reveal his true colors?
他要露出真面目了吧
All right. Am I a pig or not?
好啊 我究竟是不是豬
I'll let you feel it.
就讓你們自行感受吧
A monster.
魔物
Please be careful. This guy is a very unlucky monster to the dark elf.
請小心 這傢伙對黑暗妖精來說 是非常不吉利的魔物
You're a goblin. It has nothing to do with you.
妳是哥布林 跟妳無關吧
Puff.
噗
How dare you say that about me.
竟敢這麼說我
Are you pretending as a human?
你偽裝成人類嗎
Is it a civet?
原本是狸貓嗎
Oh, that's enough. I've had enough.
喔 夠了 我受夠了
How dare you think of me like a pig.
竟把我當成豬
I'm a super noble orc, puff.
我是超尊貴的半獸人 噗
It looks so strong.
模樣好強
Please wait a minute. I found something surprising.
請等一下 我發現很驚人的事
I found it out. I'm an angel indeed.
而竟然能發現 我果然是天使
Oh, that's amazing.
是喔 很厲害嘛
But things can get troublesome. Just murmur in your heart.
但事情會變的很麻煩 在心裡murmur就好了
I suspected the manager was a pig...
我原本懷疑店長是豬…
The type that can't hide something.
無法隱瞞的類型嘛
But he just mooed.
但他剛剛哞哞叫了
He's not a pig but a cow.
原來他不是豬 是牛
I was tricked. I thought he must be a pig.
我被騙了 我以為他一定是豬
I just said I'm an orc. Puff, puff!
就說了我是半獸人 噗 噗
It's his stand.
他這樣主張耶
But he just said "moo".
可是他剛"哞"了啊
I said "Oh", not moo.
我說的是"喔"不是哞
So you're really a pig.
那你果然是豬囉
I said I'm not a pig. I'm an orc.
就說了不是豬 是半獸人
A pig orc.
豬的半獸人
Oh, it's an orc. Orc!
喔 是半獸人 半 獸 人
You mooed again. You're really a cow.
你又哞了 果然是牛
I just said it wasn't a sound.
就說了那不是叫聲
I'm enough of this. Cry.
我受夠了啦 哭吱
Monkey. That's a lot.
猴子 太多了吧
Aren't you too greedy?
你會不會貪心過頭了
Shut up! Don't think you can get away after fooling me.
煩死了 別以為愚弄後半獸人 還能全身而退
Then how much for staying one night?
那住一晚多少錢
Accommodation for both... No way!
兩位的住宿費… 屁啦
Let's fight one-on-one.
跟我一對一決勝負吧
Hold on. She can be said to be the origin of all evil.
等等 雖然她可說是諸惡根源
But one-on-one seems...
但一對一好像…
Okay.
好啊
Don't regret it.
別後悔喔
If you win, you can call me a pig or a cow.
妳贏的話 隨便妳叫我是豬是牛都行
I got it.
我知道了
If I lose, I'll think of you like a pig.
若我輸了 就把你當豬喔
It's fair, right?
這樣很公平吧
Are you a tyrant?
妳是暴君吧
What did you say?
妳說什麼啊
So whether I win or not, I'll be considered a pig.
這樣不管我有沒有贏 都會被認為是豬嘛
-Let's do it. -Hold on. I haven't finished my words yet.
-要開始囉 -等等 話還沒說完
-Rock, Scissors... -Why is it a guessing game?
-剪刀石頭… -為什麼是猜拳
Puff.
噗
I think she deliberately said "puff" instead of "paper".
我想她應該是把"布" 故意說成"噗"吧
I know, but I've been tricked like a fool. I don't know how to respond instead.
我知道 但因一直被當笨蛋耍 反而不知道該怎麼表現了
Don't mind it. Just get to the point.
別介意 有話直說吧
Scold as much as...
用力罵…
What's wrong?
怎麼了
I suddenly feel so hot.
我突然覺得好熱
It seems I was attacked by blood burning.
看來 是中了燒血攻擊
You just fell, didn't you?
妳只是跌倒了吧
Is this... the feeling of being humiliated...
這就是…受到屈辱的感覺嗎…
Self-destructive fool.
自我毀滅的笨蛋
If I don't give you a lesson, you won't know the pain.
不給妳這種人一點教訓 就不知道痛的人
Well said.
你說的真好
But from my stand, it's my duty to protect her.
但 站在我的立場 保護她還是我的義務
I won't let you attack her again.
我不准你再攻擊她了
I've always wanted to say so.
我一直好想這樣說喔
Then you'll be beaten up together.
那你也一起被打扁吧
Jump…
跳…
Hecaton suppression...
百臂巨人壓制…
How short the distance is.
距離好短
What's wrong?
怎麼了
The landing foot is broken.
落地的腳 斷了
Lose weight.
減肥吧
Help him with healing magic.
幫他施展治療魔法吧
I can't look at it anymore.
我看不下去了
Sorry, I don't know how to cure a pig that can't fly.
抱歉 我不知道 如何治療不會飛的豬
But I can give him the last blow.
但可以給他最後一擊
Are you sure? Maybe it can increase your favorability.
妳確定嗎 搞不好能提高好感度喔
Don't move.
別亂動
I'll cast healing magic on you now.
我現在幫你施展治療魔法
Forget it. No matter what you do, your favorability won't increase much.
算了 不管怎麼做 好感度都不會增加多少
You want to save me. Why?
妳要救我 為什麼
Is there any reason to save those suffering in front of you?
拯救在眼前痛苦的人 還需要原因嗎
Then don't ask him for a treatment fee later.
那妳之後別跟他要治療費喔
Try to deny it.
努力否定啊
Puff, Lord Saint.
噗 聖女大人
It seems that his brain is injured, too.
看來他的腦部也受傷了
Come on. People always call me so.
別這樣 大家常這麼說我
She's injured more badly.
她傷得更重
Before that, manager.
在此之前 店長
I want to ask a question.
我想問個問題
It's about the travelers and adventurers who have stayed in this hotel.
是關於至今來這間旅館投宿的 旅行家和冒險家的事
The reason why the monster orc purposely became a human to run this hotel.
魔物半獸人 特地變成人類 經營這家旅館的原因
What is it...
究竟是…
Puff, bad things will be found out sooner or later.
噗 夜路走多豬來敲門了
Are you a pig farmer?
你是養豬業者嗎
Since Lord Saint is here, I can confess to you.
既然聖女大人在此 我就能跟您懺悔了
As you expected, many travelers, adventurers and foreign businessmen came to this hotel.
如您所料 有許多旅行家冒險家 他國商人來這間旅館
Only come to the orc's hotel.
只來半獸人的旅館
They were tired from long trips and adventures.
因長途旅行和冒險而疲累
When they arrived at the hotel, they were usually unprepared and careless.
抵達旅館時 通常都缺乏戒備且大意
Could it be...
難道…
Right. When they were careless, I poured it into the dishes...
沒錯 我趁他們大意之時 在料理中倒入…
Poison.
下毒
Medicine with nourishing effect.
有滋養效果的藥
Nourishing... It doesn't seem quite right.
滋養… 好像不太對
But if the amount isn't right, you'll be more tired after eating it.
但若份量拿捏不對 吃下後反而會疲累加倍
I only hope the guests who came to stay can recover a little bit.
我只是希望 來住宿的客人 多少能恢復點精神
But it'll backfire if I don't do it right.
但一個不小心 就會造成反效果
It's the problem of usage and amount, right?
是用法和份量的問題對吧
I'm a stupid teammate who put my guests in danger.
我是個害客人陷入危險的豬隊友
Wait a second.
稍等一下喔
Carla, he doesn't seem to be a bad guy.
卡菈 他好像不是壞人
It doesn't seem right for us to get angry at him.
我們對他發脾氣 好像不對喔
I see.
原來如此
Then we can't blame him.
那就不能怪罪了
-Guilty. -You sentenced him immediately.
-有罪 -妳這是直接判刑
Puff, please forgive me.
噗 請原諒我
Mr. Alvin.
埃爾文先生
Are you going to sell me to a human trafficker?
你打算把我賣給人口販子嗎
It'll bring trouble to the human trafficker.
會給人口販子帶來困擾吧
I'm going to solve the guild's "collecting herbs" task.
我要去解公會的"採集藥草"任務
I see. By the way, Mr. Alvin.
這樣啊 對了埃爾文先生
Can you stop shaking so much? I'll get carsick.
你能別晃得這麼厲害嗎 我會暈車
Get off then.
那妳就下來啊
Why do you just sit...
妳幹嘛理所當然地坐在…
Mr. Alvin, there's someone ahead.
埃爾文先生 前面有人耶
A traveler. No, it's an old woman.
旅行家 不 是老婆婆
Is she not feeling well?
她是不是不舒服
Let's go and ask her.
去問問看好了
Do you want her to pull this cart?
你想讓她拉這輛推車嗎
Why would you think so?
妳為何會這麼想
So you want to chat her up.
所以是搭訕囉
Stop talking about it.
別再說了
Excuse me.
請問
Old lady, are you all right? Are you not...
老婆婆您還好嗎 是不是不舒…
Miss, you look idle.
小姐 妳看起來很閒
Do you want to have fun with us?
要不要跟我們去找樂子
Don't chat her up.
不要搭訕人家
Young people are so energetic.
年輕人精神真好
I just sit here and take a rest.
我只是坐在這休息
There will be monsters here.
這裡會出現魔物
Let us take you home.
我們送您回家吧
Is that okay?
可以嗎
You approach people in trouble with gentle words.
看你用溫柔言語接近有困難的人
Saying sweet words to take a woman home.
花言巧語 帶女性回家
You seem natural and skilled.
手法自然 又很熟練
Your words...
妳的措辭…
But you're not popular. It's unbelievable.
但卻不受歡迎 太不可思議了
It's none of your business.
關妳屁事
Should I just go with you?
要不要恭敬不如從命呢
The dull guy didn't find out I'm a witch.
沒發現我是魔女的遲鈍傢伙
And I need male internal organs to make drugs.
我正好需要男性內臟來製藥
You get off and walk.
妳下來走啦
It's a hint to piggyback me.
這是要背我的暗示
And there's a dark elf.
還有黑暗精靈
What an excellent "material" that's hard to get.
是難以得手的優良"素材"
I can't miss it.
絕不能錯過
Young man, take this.
年輕人 這個送你吧
What's it?
這是什麼
It's my self-made medicine for restoring physical strength.
這是我自製的恢復體力藥物
I wanted to drink it later. But I'll give it to you.
我本來想之後喝 但送你吧
It's a great help to me.
幫了我大忙啊
Dull guy, that's highly toxic.
遲鈍的傢伙 那是劇毒
Let the man be weak first. And the woman...
先讓男的無力化 女的就…
What's wrong?
怎麼了
It's hard to pull out the cork.
好難拔出軟木塞
Why would you dress like this?
誰叫你要穿成這樣
Give it to me. I'll open it for you.
給我吧 我幫你打開
-I'm sorry. -It's no big deal.
-抱歉 -小事一樁
Mr. Alvin, you can't live without me.
埃爾文先生沒有我就無法過活了
I can live without you.
沒有妳我也能過活
I'm sick of it.
討厭
What are you doing?
妳在幹嘛啊
Mr. Alvin, come on. Lick it like a dog.
埃爾文先生 快像狗一樣用舔的
Are you kidding me?
開什麼玩笑
Three-second rule.
三秒規則
The liquid doesn't apply to this rule.
液體不適用這個規則吧
Why would you throw it when you can't open it?
哪有人打不開就用摔的
No, it... Well...
不是的 這是…那個…
Right, that's poison.
對 那是毒藥
What poison?
什麼毒藥啊
You just wanted me to lick...
那妳剛才還要我舔…
-Idiot. -Shut up, bastard.
-蠢蛋 -閉嘴 混蛋
Mr. Alvin, you're too careless.
埃爾文先生太不小心了
You trusted someone who met for the first time too much.
太相信初次見面的人
This...
這…
Look at her weird dress-up. She's a witch.
看她詭異的打扮 她是魔女啊
It seems right after you say so.
經妳這麼說的確很像啦
And I'm a beauty.
而我是美魔女
I can't tell that.
我看不出來
Do you have any proof that I'm a witch?
妳有我是魔女的證據嗎
Proof...
證據啊…
Just try to add the proof later.
證據這種東西 之後再想辦法加上去就好了
What a rascal.
壞蛋
But is it really dangerous to trust strangers... too much?
但太相信陌生人的確有危險…嗎
Oh no, the rare material...
糟糕 難得找到的素材…
I'm so sad.
我好難過
I wanted to treat you to a delicious meal when I reached home.
原本想到家時 打算請兩位吃頓美味料理
My son died of an infectious disease.
我兒子因傳染病逝世
My husband died early. I'm so lonely.
丈夫也早逝 我好寂寞
I haven't felt warmth for a long time.
許久不曾得到了人情溫暖
I just feel happy...
我只是單純地感到高興…
Do you think this will win our sympathy?
妳以為這樣能博得我們的同情嗎
Who would believe your nonsense?
誰會相信妳的鬼話
It's really not that simple.
果然沒這麼簡單
But I suddenly feel hungry.
不過 我突然覺得很餓
Come on. Get on.
來 上車吧
Just pay with delicious food for taking you home.
到您家的酬勞 就用美味料理支付吧
It's too simple.
太簡單了吧
Here's my house.
這裡就是我家
Sorry for bothering you.
打擾了
There are so many books.
好多書喔
It'll be easy to burn.
這麼多書 很容易燒吧
Is it a crime preview?
犯罪預告嗎
You may sit anywhere.
隨便找地方坐吧
I'll prepare the drinks.
我去準備飲料
Thank you.
謝謝
Phew.
嘿咻
I'll have a glass of raw first.
先來一杯生的
Are you an old man?
妳是大叔嗎
And what's the raw thing?
還有 什麼東西生的
Fresh lettuce juice.
鮮榨生菜果汁
Troublesome brats.
麻煩的死小孩們
Forget it. Let them settle down with herbal tea with paralytic poison.
算了 用加了麻痺毒藥的花草茶 讓他們安分點吧
Here you go. Have some herbal tea.
來 請喝花草茶
Is it a legal "herb"?
是合法的"花草"吧
Illegal elf, shut up.
非法精靈閉嘴
Sorry, she's a little self-righteous.
不好意思 她有點自以為是
It's good to be energetic.
有精神是好事啊
Come on. Please drink herbal tea.
來 請喝花草茶
Okay. Thank you for that.
好 那我就不客氣了
Are you all right?
妳沒事吧
I'm okay. It just spilled on my clothes.
沒事 只是灑到衣服上
Well, are you okay?
那 妳沒事吧
No, I just want to lie down.
不 我只是突然想躺下
How loud.
嗓門好大
And read a book by the way.
順便想看個書
Get up and tidy up.
快起來整理一下
Old lady, go and get changed.
老婆婆去換個衣服吧
I'll clean here up.
這裡我來打掃
Sorry for that. The cleaning tools are over there.
真不好意思 打掃工具在那
Sheer dumb luck.
狗屎運的傢伙
Mr. Alvin, here's the rag.
埃爾文先生 抹布在這
Oh, thank you.
喔 謝啦
Are you kidding me? That's my cloak.
開什麼玩笑 這是我的披風
Oh right, let's use that.
對了 用那個吧
Well, hurry up and clean it up.
好 快點打掃乾淨吧
Clean the whole room by the way.
也順便打掃整個房間吧
There's dust everywhere.
到處都是灰塵
How rare that you say something decent.
難得妳也能說點像樣的話
It must be hard for the old lady to clean up alone.
只有老婆婆一人 打掃很辛苦吧
What's wrong with her? She said some decent lines.
這傢伙是怎麼了 竟然說些正派的台詞
It won't be found out if I steal a few books while it's messy.
然後趁弄亂之際偷走兩三本書 也不會被發現吧
It seems that I'm wrong.
看來是我會錯意了
What are you doing?
你們在做什麼
We want to clean the room by the way.
想說順便打掃房間
I'm so sorry about that.
真是不好意思
Old lady, what's that?
老婆婆 那是什麼
It's a scented candle.
是香氛蠟燭
Its fragrance can make you relax.
香氣能讓人放鬆喔
You are rare visitors to my house.
你們是難得來我家的客人
Have a good rest.
好好放鬆一下吧
It's actually a candle with a sleeping effect.
其實是有安眠效果的蠟燭
I've taken the antidote, so I'll be fine.
我已吃下解藥所以不會有事
If you smell it for ten minutes, you'll feel strongly sleepy.
只要聞十分鐘 便會產生強烈睡意
Be careful with the fire!
小心火燭
What... What if it burns the books?
萬… 萬一燒到書怎麼辦
Can't you remind us before you did it?
妳行動前是不會先口頭提醒啊
Sorry. I'm sorry.
對不起對不起
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
對不起 我只能說對不起
Sorry, I have a strong sense of disaster prevention.
對不起 我的防災意識太強了
Sorry, I can't stop this disaster.
對不起我阻止不了這個災害自走砲
I'll go and get changed.
我去換件衣服
What a relief. She's not angry.
太好了 她沒生氣
How could there be such a miracle?
怎麼可能有這種奇蹟
She's just too angry to curse you.
人家只是氣到不想對妳大罵吧
Hurry up and clean it up.
趕快整理打掃
When she comes back, kneel and apologize. Then leave quickly.
等人家回來後下跪道歉 然後趕快離開
Aren't we going to have delicious food with the old lady?
不跟老婆婆一起圍爐 吃美味料理了嗎
Who could eat together in such an awkward atmosphere?
誰還能在尷尬的氣氛裡圍爐啊
Why are you so flustered?
為何這麼慌張呢
Old lady, you're back.
老婆婆 妳回來啦
You agreed to eat the dish I made.
說好了要一起吃我做的料理啊
But we're about to leave.
但我們差不多該離開了
Shut up and eat.
閉嘴 快吃
She's really angry.
人家果然生氣了
And what's in that pot? It'll definitely kill us.
還有那鍋是什麼 絕對是殺人料理
It looks terrible.
看起來好難吃
I looked forward to it.
虧我還那麼期待
And she continues to freeze the atmosphere.
然後這傢伙繼續搞僵氣氛
Can I cast a spell on it to make it delicious?
我能施加變好吃的料理嗎
I remember the spell is...
我記得咒語是…
Become delicious, Moe Moe...
料理變好吃 萌萌…
Kyun.
破
Get out of here, please.
拜託快滾
What do you want to do?
你們到底想幹嘛
Didn't I ask you to get out?
我不是說要你們快滾嗎
Why are you still here?
妳還在這幹嘛
You can tell by looking at me.
看就知道啊
Cooking, of course.
當然是做料理
I think it means something else.
我只覺得是別的意思
I was unlucky just now. I flipped your food.
剛才運氣不好 打飛了老婆婆的料理
To make up for it,
為了贖罪
I want to cook
我要用妳家的食材
by using your ingredients.
來做料理
How annoying.
煩死了
-Can I decline it? -No.
-我能拒絕嗎 -不能
Carla, have you ever done cooking?
卡菈 妳曾做過料理嗎
No.
不曾
I think so.
我想也是
But I can eat.
但我會吃
Whatever. The ingredients are in the store at the back.
隨便妳吧 食材放在後面的倉庫
Thank you, old lady.
謝謝老婆婆
Is it all right?
這樣好嗎
She won't listen to anything, anyway.
反正不管說什麼她都不會聽吧
Then let her finish quickly.
那就只能讓她快快結束吧
I hope it can finish safely.
希望能平安結束
Sorry to keep you waiting.
讓你們久等了
Mr. Alvin, it's great.
埃爾文先生 好棒喔
There are many ingredients I haven't seen before.
有許多我沒看過的食材
We've seen it before!
看過好嗎
Where have you been?
你之前都到哪去了
After coming out of the beginner dungeon, I went after butterflies.
從新手迷宮出來後 我就去追蝴蝶了
Then I got lost.
追著追著就迷路了
Carla, you don't want to cook him, do you?
卡菈 妳該不會想把他做成料理吧
No, not today.
不 今天不做
Not for all your life.
一輩子都不准做
What do you want to do?
你到底想做什麼
Making a legend.
製作傳說
I don't have time for your nonsense.
我沒空跟妳鬼扯
Don't touch me.
別隨便碰我
Old lady, this way, please.
老婆婆 這邊請
Please stand here. Don't move.
請站在這裡別亂動
What? Aren't you going to cook?
怎麼 妳不是要做料理嗎
Emergency food... Altargaia, please help me.
緊急食… 奧爾特蓋亞先生 請來幫我的忙
Okay, got it.
好的 收到
Put this ingredient here. Put this ingredient there.
這個食材放這 那裡放這個食材
Okay, that's about it.
好 大概就是這樣
What are you going to do?
妳要做什麼
The so-called cooking is processing ingredients.
所謂的做料理 就是加工食材
I'm going to complete the processing with magic.
我打算用魔法補足加工
Can this be considered cooking?
這樣能算做料理嗎
Don't worry.
請放心
The food I cook is absolutely edible. Probably.
我做的料理絕對能吃 應該吧
Nice.
好
It's not nice.
好個頭啦
What's that? The old lady was eaten.
那是什麼 老婆婆被吃掉了
I said "absolutely edible."
我說了"絕對能吃"啊
Who wants to be an "edible" ingredient?
誰要當"能吃"的食材啊
What kind of weird food is this?
這算哪門子的獵奇料理啦
That's a nice name.
不錯的料理名稱喔
It looks awful, okay?
看起來很難吃好嗎
I think I just heard something.
剛才我好像聽到什麼聲音
It looks like it's ready.
好像做好了
Old lady, are you okay?
老婆婆 妳沒事吧
You haven't been digested, have you?
沒被消化掉吧
What's wrong with me...
我到底怎麼了…
Who are you?
您是哪位
It's the old lady.
是老婆婆啊
She doesn't look like the old lady at all.
外表一點都不老婆婆啊
Because I chose ingredients with beauty effects.
因為我選了有美容效果的食材啊
It's beyond the realm of beauty effects.
這已經超越美容效果的境界了吧
Please look.
請看
What... What's going on?
這這這是怎麼回事
Rejuvenation. How is that possible?
返老還童 怎麼可能
Rejuvenation magic. No, it's a ritual.
返老還童的魔法 不對 是儀式
Whatever it is, the operation of retrospective style only appears in legends or stories.
不管是哪個 回溯時間類型的術式 只在傳說中或故事裡出現啊
Who exactly are you?
妳到底是什麼人
All right. Please bear in mind.
好啊 請妳牢記在心
-Standing like a Chinese peony. -Stressful Rafflesia.
-站姿如芍藥 -給人壓力的霸王花
-Sitting like a Moutan peony. -Disappointing flytrap.
-坐姿如牡丹 -令人遺憾的捕蠅草
-Running like a lily. -Devastating pitcher plant.
-奔跑身姿如百合 -毀滅性的豬龍草
The name is...
其名為
Self-proclaimed.
自稱
The cleric, Carla.
聖職人員 卡菈
-Geez. -What?
-討厭啦 -幹嘛啦
You're so annoying.
你很煩耶
-What a good tacit understanding. -I was telling the truth.
-默契真好 -我說的是實話啊
"NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW" I'll report the title of the next episode.
(下集預告) 下集標題由我來報
"BUT ALVIN WAS SERIOUSLY INJURED. MISFORTUNES NEVER COME SINGLY." Gosh, do they read titles with so many words?
(但埃爾文卻受了重傷 屋漏偏逢連夜雨) 天啊他們都唸這麼多字的標題嗎
ALVIN ALSO HAD TO TAKE OFF HIS ARMOR AND REST. THE TWO BEGAN TO QUARREL AGAIN. THEIR RELATIONSHIP MIGHT CHANGE.
(埃爾文也不得不脫下盔甲 閉目養神) (此時兩人又開始爭吵 關係可能因此產生變化)
"THE QUARREL BETWEEN ALVIN AND CARLA" Not only were they attacked by thieves
(埃爾文和卡菈爭吵的台詞) 旅途途中不僅遭到盜賊襲擊
"IS THE MOST IMPORTANT PART OF THIS WORK." during the journey, but they also met a golem.
(明明就是本作品最重要的喬段) 還遇到了魔像
"BUT IN THIS ERA, WHETHER IT'S ROLE AUDITION OR RECORDING," Alvin and Carla overcame many obstacles
(但在這個時代 不論是角色試鏡還是錄製工作) 埃爾文和卡菈如以往那樣
"ACCESS TO THE RECORDING STUDIO IS VERY LIMITED." as before.
(能進入錄音室的人數十分有限) 突破重重難關
"ALL WORKED TOGETHER TO OVERCOME THE DIFFICULTIES. THAT'S EPISODE SIX." But... There are too many words.
(大家一起努力合作度過難關的第六話) 但… 字太多了啦
"STAY TUNED" Who reads...
(要繼續觀看喔) 誰唸…